## PETER MOLNAR

 ■ e-mail
 mail@petermolnar.net

 ↓ phone
 +447592011721

S web <a href="https://petermolnar.net">https://petermolnar.net</a>

Github <a href="https://github.com/petermolnar">https://github.com/petermolnar</a>

in Linkedin <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/petermolnareu">https://www.linkedin.com/in/petermolnareu</a>

## **SUMMARY**

I made my first website in 1999. Since then I worked in nearly all parts of e-commerce: from frontend, through backend - with a detour to embedded development - to system administration. I believe in optimization, Open Source and Free Software, and to research the best, existing solution for a problem.

## KEY SKILLS

- 10 years of system administration in DevOps/SRE environment:
  - CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu, FreeNAS
  - automating and maintaning 2000+ physical node, 200PB+ capacity BigData Hadoop/Hive clusters
  - managing web service stacks with nginx, apache, PHP, MySQL, SQLite
  - setting up and running email systems with spam- and content filtering, including DKIM and DMARC
  - developing and configuring monitoring solutions with rsyslog, monit, nagios, graphite, grafana, elasticsearch, collectd, InfluxDB
  - enforcing configuration management with Puppet, and ansible
  - version controlling with Git, SVN, MKS Integrity
- good understanding of cloud technologies, experience with DigitalOcean, Google, and AWS
- scripting and programming experience in Python, PHP, bash, Perl, C, Java, CSS, HTML
- structured data exposure, WordPress plugin and theme development expertise
- spoken languages: native Hungarian and professional level English
- full driving license (B)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## System Administrator at Booking.com Ltd

from 2013-08, Cambridge, remote to Amsterdam Headquarters

Since 2015 Apr I'm working on automating BigData stacks - multiple Hadoop clusters, some over 2000 nodes. I've refactored most of our legacy autonomous system to handle exponential growth and to align with the rest of the company codebase.

In 2014, I worked on monitoring, aiming to replace nagios, to reduce on-call alerts, and increase automation. Solution included adding self-healing processes to individual nodes, and preparing work for centralized logging.

Until mid 2014, I worked in communications, maintaining mail, fax, and proxy services. I migrated the former proprietary virus and content filtering to open solutions.

#### Partner Integration Engineer at GREE UK Limited

from 2012-11 to 2013-08, London

I was introducing and supporting external partners to use the company stack of load-balanced weband database clusters, PHP and Java frameworks to develop iOS and Android based games.

## Program Developer at Evosoft Hungary Kft.

from 2011-11 to 2012-09, Budapest

I was part of a project porting an embedded code base to be interfaced with C# under Windows for Siemens.

## Systems Engineer at **Knorr-Bremse AG**

from 2011-03 to 2011-11, Budapest

I was developing, testing, and documenting time- and safety critical, hard real-time, automotive C software and deployed continuous integration for code quality metrics.

## System Administrator at Arkon Zrt.

from 2009-06 to 2011-02, Budapest

I maintained, upgraded and migrated - both in team and alone - high availability web- and mail services for the market leader real estate search engine in Hungary; occasionally helped with back office and Windows support.

# Computer Laboratory Maintainer at **Óbuda University**

from 2007-09 to 2009-06, Budapest

I maintained Windows and Ubuntu machines and deployed an operating system imaging service with Finnix and PXE that could cope with slow networks. I regularly held classes in basics of C, atmel, embedded, and web programming, and kept some university WordPress sites running.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **BSc Electrical Engineer at Obuda University**

from 2004-09 to 2009-05, Budapest

Specialized in embedded systems and industrial system automation. Awarded with Thesis Award from Budapest and Pest County Chamber of Engineers in 2009.

## **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

I used to make web presence for small companies between 2003 and 2010 on a custom PHP CMS. I moved to WordPress in 2007, wrote a few mildly successfull plugins for it. I ended up writing a simple static site generator in Python 3 to learn it, and to integrate <a href="Indieweb">Indieweb</a> building blocks into it. I can write HTML and CSS by hand.

To keep myself up to date with technologies out of my day job I kept running bare metal servers for web, mail, XMPP, and ZFS storage services.

I'm an active practicioner of martial arts and archery.